# PHAN NGỌC QUỲNH HƯƠNG

MARKETING MANAGER







## SUMMARY

Having 6 years of experience in the marketing industry, I am a motivated marketing professional with solid adaptability, a willingness to learn, and sharp interpersonal insight. I am experienced as a team leader in a professional cooperative working environment. As a perfectionist, I always strive to achieve the highest possible standard at any given task.

#### EDUCATION

#### ADVANCED MASTER OF MARKETING AND COMMUNICATION

Solvay Brussels School • On-going

• Relevant coursework: Strategic Marketing Management, Marketing Planning, Retail and Distribution, Media Management, Digital Communication, Leadership & Team Empowerment

#### BACHELOR OF INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

University of Economics Ho Chi Minh City • 2016-2019

- Graduated from High Quality Program, GPA 3.0
- Top 10 Entrepreneurship Program 2018

#### CORE COMPETENCIES

- Strategic Planning
- Project Planning
- Leadership
- Digital management
- Verbal communication
- Social media management Content Creation
- Market Research
- Strong Problem-solving
- Communication Skills
- Adaptability and Flexibility
- Time management

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## PRANDA JEWELRY PUBLIC COMPANY LIMITED (TOP LUXURY BRAND BASED IN THAILAND)

Marketing Leader - Head of Vietnam Marketing Team • 03/2021 - Present

- Managed the marketing and communication activities for 2 luxury brands: PRIMA JEWELRY & PRIMA ART
- Built strategic marketing plans including forecasts, new product launches, advertisements, and promotions for retail, B2B, co-branding, and authorized retailers projects
- Managed and allocated marketing budgets to ensure a quarterly ROAS of at least 5 times.
- Developed online channels (Facebook, Instagram, Tiktok, LinkedIn, Zalo Mini app, Website,...) and tailored the content pillar, promotion and brand image for each platform
- Trained & and inspired team about product knowledge, building customer approach way, analyzing customer and market insight
- Developed monthly promotion programs that suit customers' preferences and achieve sales target
- Collaborated with shopping malls (Diamond Plaza, Lotte Department Store) or partners (Haper's Bazaar, Universe Vietnam, VITA Clinic,...) to host exclusive events tailored for VIP members
- Accomplished 4,000,000,000VND through social commerce channels in 2021 (lock-down period) and achieved 12% company growth vs 2.1% budgeted

## HA TRAN GROUP (FnB & REAL ESTATE COMPANY)

Senior Marketing Executive • 7/2020 - 3/2021

- Managed and trained a group of 4 team members to deploy marketing campaigns
- Created and developed all online platforms: Facebook, Website, Grab, Gojek, ShopeeFood
- Implemented advertisements across multiple platforms including Facebook Ads, SEO, SEM, billboard displays, roadshows,...
- Coordinated the production and distribution of POSM, including displays, signage, product packaging, and promotional materials,
- Accomplished 92,000,000VND on the website, grab and shopeefood platform within 1st month (free advertisements)

## DIAGEO VIETNAM (GLOBAL BRAND OF PREMIUM DRINKS BASED IN BRITISH)

Commercial Marketing Admin • 12/2019 - 7/2020

- Monitor the monthly performance of more than 2,000 outlets nationwide to assess eligibility for incentives.
- Follow up on and draft contracts for around 100 of potential outlets per month
- Coordinated with the internal team to deploy monthly campaigns and events
- Managed marketing databases, CRM systems, campaign performance metrics, and budget tracking.

### AESTHETIC AND HEALTH COMPANY (COSMETICS TECHNOLOGY AND COSMECEUTICALS COMPANY)

Marketing Executive (Online) • 11/2019 - 12/2020

- Managed the marketing and communication activities for 4 brands: iS Clinical, TiZo, Allergan, Mesoestetic
- Tailored content pillar for each brand on multi-media channels: e-news, blog, community groups, fan page, and emailing,...
- Prepared documents and arranged webinar weekly to approach potential customers
- Supported Pharmacology department research about the products' features to trainee other staff
- Accomplishments: 62% increase in reach & 21% increase in revenue within 1st month (free advertising)

## MEDIA POST JSC. (DIRECT MARKETING AGENCY)

Marketing Intern • 5/2019 - 10/2019

- Coordinated all relevant activities to organize events at luxury apartments for Children's Day and the Mid-Autumn Festival (such as New Saigon, Tropic Garden, Riviera Point, etc.) to fulfill client specifications.
- Implemented event/pop-up sales at shopping malls (Lotte, Big C, Cresent Mall, SC Vivo City, etc.), and office buildings (AB Tower, Green Power, VTP, etc.) for Vietnam Australia International School (VAS).
- Support to participate in events and fairs to introduce the company's services and collect potential customer information (Vietfood & Beverage Propack 2019, Zhejiang Export Fair 2019, etc.)